## Shiva Srinivasan

## Sr QA Engineer

Key leader within the dedicated product team experienced in building consensus amongst stakeholders by defining and championing shared product vision of what needs to be built. Talent for conveying clear and compelling narrative and enthusiasm for creating vital functionality. Strong desire for continuous improvement and proven ability to think strategically and act tactically about product quality.

## **Work History**

#### 2015-06 -Current

### Sr QA Engineer

Navex Global Inc, Portland, OR

- Design and implement automation framework in the organization
- Being the QA advocate working with product and developers to deliver a quality product
- Be a root cause analysis champion
- Instill culture of Quality in the organization
- Mentor new QA engineers and provide support
- Be the subject matter expert for all identity and access management related queries for business and IT
- Be a root cause analysis champion

#### 2009-01 -2013-01

## **Application Developer/Conversion Lead**

CenturyLink, Vancouver, WA

- Hired to be part of a 10 member team to support client company acquisition to design and develop a conversion process to create quality, usable, secure and scalable systems using agile methodology
- Key contributions
- Built performance optimization solutions reducing operation costs by over 50% with \$120K annual savings
- Designed real time reporting tools to track conversion timelines and accuracy
- Spearheaded multiple development projects post

#### Contact

#### **Address**

Beaverton, OR, 97007

#### Phone

720-233-2416

#### E-mail

sivkumar.s@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/sivkumars

#### **Skills**

Domain Expertise



Strategic planning



CI/CD Implementation



Automation knowledge



Training and mentoring



Team Leadership



Very Good

## Software

conversion driving continuous improvement to processes, systems, work flow and customer responsiveness

## 2005-01 - Application Developer

Qwest, Denver, CO

- Recruited to develop and maintain a mission critical application
- Responsible to deliver solutions that meet business objectives ensuring adherence to change management processes Key contributions
- Implemented process improvements and designed automated solutions increasing service levels and stability
- Provided CPU reduction solutions on multiple legacy applications saving over \$500k annually
- Reduced the application downtime by optimizing cycle times on nightly batch activities

## **Education**

2009-01

# 2000-01 - Bachelor Degree: Electronics and Communication Engineering

## **Accomplishments**

- Conceptualized and designed Selenium/c# based automation framework
- Performance optimization that resulted in savings of over \$500k annually

Jira

Selenium

Very Good

Cypress

Very Good

Git

Very Good

Team City

Very Good

Jenkins

AWS

# Good

Very Good

## Languages

C#

Superior

Javascript

Advanced

Node is

Intermediate

React

